ERIKA LOPEZ

Business Analyst - Change Management

915-929-2209



eylopez8686@gmail.com



12769 Kingsbury, El Paso, TX 79928



SUMMARY

Highly experienced Business Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in change management and field readiness, creating idea change management portals, assessing and implementing processes to support adoption changes, and creating 'problem-solving' structures.

EDUCATION

Arizona State University

Bachelor's Degree in Mass Communications 2004 – 2010

SKILLS

- SQL
- JavaScript
- Node
- API
- Sharepoint
- Excel Macros
- PowerApps
- Change management (9 years)
- · Microsoft Office
- Photoshop
- Tableau

AWARDS

- Excellence Award
- Recipient of \$10,000 bonus award
- Exceeded Expectations during 9 years of tenure

CERTIFICATIONS

- Project Management Certification University of Austin
- SQL Certified
- SharePoint Certified

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Business Analyst - Change Management

Charles Schwab | 09/2014 - 10/2023 40 hours per week Grade 56 Salary (yearly) \$90,000 +/ bonuses

- Outstanding verbal and written communication, collaboration, negotiation, and influencing skills to lead an environment driven by stakeholders, leaders, and teamwork.
- Support communication efforts Support the design, development, management, and delivery of communications interfacing with Corporate Communications across the firm.
- Assess and measure the change impact conduct impact analyses through SQL sequences, assess change readiness, develop leading and lagging key principle indicators (KPIs), and identify and manage risk with key stakeholders and leadership.
- Consult and coach project team leaders, stakeholders, and subject matter experts (SMEs).
- Proven experience in developing and evolving change management program structures and portals.
- Manage communication channels including facilitating largescale meetings and Intranet to ensure ongoing engagement.
- Engaging with many areas within the organization to align key stakeholders, increase awareness of various change initiatives, and drive business results.
- Influencing key stakeholders without direct authority.
- Utilizing the change management process and toolkit, identify stakeholders, impacts, and develop change mitigation strategies and tools.
- Supporting the creation and sustainment of a change management practice within and across the business to create employee readiness and engagement.

Business Analyst - Continued

- Cultivate employee engagement, diversity and inclusiveness by chair and co-chair employee resource groups.
- Support business needs through data analytics gathered via SQL and other internal resources.
- review data analytics to improve or create new business processes.
- Create internal and external policies and procedures.
- Communicate internally and externally with stakeholders, senior leadership and employees across the firm to introduce, develop, and present, policies, procedures, and products.

Employee Resource Groups (ERGs)

Chair - Community Services Ambassadors

Charles Schwab | 2016- 2024

- Secure non-profits for volunteer projects and grants.
- Cultivate relationships with non-profit organization board members.
- · Manage a team of ten ambassadors.
- Organize Schwab Volunteer Week- A two-week volunteer project consisting of different non-profits within the community.
- · Organized Season of Giving event.
- Secure funding for events and projects.
- · profit and loss balance sheets.

Co-Chair - Family Network

Charles Schwab | 2023 - 2024

- Plan local and national events for company.
- Engage employees to take full advantage of resources provided by company.
- Supporting diverse families.
- Secure funding for projects and events.
- · Profit and loss balance sheets.

Boys & Girls Club of El Paso

September 2014 - October 2023 Volunteer & Chair

Humane Society of El Paso

September 2014 - October 2023 Volunteer & Chair

Junior Achievement of El Paso

September 2014 - October 2023 Teacher & Chair

Child Crisis Center

September 2014 - October 2023 Volunteer & Chair